# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi, this is Chef Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
Today, I will share with you a dish.
# 粉条丸子
Yam glass noodle veggie balls
# 首先我们准备适量的红薯粉条放入盆中
First, we need some yam glass noodle
# 然后加入80度左右的热水泡发30分钟
Add 80°C (176F) hot water and soak it for 30 minutes.
# 同学们以下辅料众多请做好笔记
Please pay attention. There will be lots of complementary ingredients.
# 准备莲藕1小块去皮之后切成小颗粒备用
Dice a small chunk of lotus root after peeling off its skin.
# 加莲藕可以增加丸子爽脆的口感
Adding the lotus root will create more crunchy texture.
# 准备香菇3个从中间片开之后切碎备用
Prepare three shiitake mushrooms. Cut them in half and mince them.
# 加香菇可以代替味精增加鲜味
Shiitake mushroom can be used to substitute MSG.
# 准备胡萝卜1小块切碎备用
Mince a small chunk of carrot.
# 准备青瓜1小块切碎备用
Mince a small chunk of cucumber.
# 加胡萝卜和青瓜可以增加红绿色
Adding cucumber and carrot will make the veggie balls colorful
# 准备大葱2根对半切开之后切碎备用
Cut two spring onions in half and mince them.
# 准备大红椒半个去掉辣椒籽之后切碎备用
Prepare a red bell pepper, remove its seeds, and mince it.
# 加大红椒的目的是增加鲜甜味
Red bell pepper will provide sweetness and umami to the veggie ball.
# 最后将泡发好的粉条剁碎备用
Lastly, mince the pre-soaked yam glass noodle
# 粉条可以增加丸子的韧劲
yam glass noodle will provide a chewy texture to the veggie balls.
# 下一步开始调糊
Now, let's make the batter.
# 盆中加入普通面粉400克
Add 400g of regular flour.
# 面粉和颗粒辅料的比例为1:1
The ratio of flour and complementary ingredients should be 1:1.
# 盆中加入酵母粉1小勺（约1克）
Add a small spoon of yeast (About 1g).
# 加入食用盐2勺半调底味（约5克）
Add two and a half spoons of salt (About 5g).
# 然后我们加水之前先搅拌均匀
Before we add in water, we need to mix them well.
# 搅拌均匀之后少量多次的加入热水搅拌
Add a little bit of hot water at a time.
# 同学们水温最好在60度以上
The water should be above 60 degrees Celsius.
# 然后加入1小块豆腐捏碎
Add a small chunk of crushed Tofu.
# 加豆腐可以增加成菜的香味
Tofu will provide aroma to the meatball.
# 再加入和豆腐等量的面粉搅拌均匀收干水份
Then, add equivalent amount of flour to soak up excess water.
# 将其搅拌至可以挤出丸子即可
Mix the batter until you can squeeze meatball from it.
# 然后我们再加入适量的植物油拌匀
Then, add some vegetable oil.
# 加植物油的目的是减少面团的粘度
This will reduce the stickness of the batter.
# 搅拌均匀之后再加入所有切好的辅料拌匀
Then, we add in all of the complementary ingredients.
# 辅料拌匀之后下一步开始制作
Mix them well.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
We need to heat up the wok first.
# 锅烧热之后举盆之力加入宽油
Add Kuan You (literally "broad oil")
# 将油温烧至5成热
Heat up the oil to 50%.
# 油温5成热之后将面团挤成大小均匀的丸子下锅
Squeeze the batter into meatballs and put them in the oil.
# 丸子下锅之后转中火炸至飘起来即可
After putting the meatballs in, turn the stove to medium and wait until they start to float.
# 中途需要将提前炸黄的丸子捞出
We have to take out the meatballs that are already golden.
# 这一步的目的是防止炸糊
To prevent them from burning.
# 最后炸至丸子全部飘起来之后捞出备用
Take out all the meatballs until they are floating.
# 然后将油温升至6成热之后再下入丸子复炸10秒钟
Then, heat up the oil to 60% and re-fry the meatballs for 10 seconds.
# 这一步的目的是将表皮炸脆
This will make the meatballs crispy.
# 10秒钟之后将丸子捞出即可上菜
After 10 seconds, take the meatballs out.
# 一道外酥里嫩的粉条炸丸子就制作完成
A delicious glass noodle meatball is finished.
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，所有蔬菜瓜果可以根据个人喜爱添加，最好全部切成小颗粒
# 第二，调面糊必须用60度以上的热水，这样调的糊炸出来更嫩
# 第三，炸至的时候油温不能太高，且边炸边捞出炸好的丸子
# 第四，此菜不仅可以加素菜还可以加入猪肉末或者牛肉
# 粉条丸子的技术总结完毕
Technical Summary:
First, you can add any vegetable you want, but remember to finely mince them.
Second, the water has to be above 60 degree Celsius when making the batter. This will make the meatballs more tender.
Third, don't heat up the oil to high. You also have to take out the meatballs that are already fully fried.
Fourth, you can also add minced pork or beef to this dish if you prefer.
That's all for glass noodle meatball's technical summary.